STEPH MILLER | DATA ANALYST

Hermitage, TN 37076| (219) 508-0935 | samiller4@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/steph-miller-4142sm | github.com/StephMiller4

ABOUT ME

I have worked in a few different fields but in all of my jobs, I have always been most excited about data and numbers. The things that will make me a successful data analyst are that I am able to visualize many parts of a project and am a creative problem solver.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python including Pandas and Numpy

Tableau

Excel

✓ SQL

✓ Git/GitHub

PowerBI

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

Nashville, TN

Data Analyst Apprentice | September 2022 - Present

Intensive full-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem-solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- · Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL and sqlalchemy
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking

PROJECTS

- Lahman Baseball | Team Project Used SQL to analyze a dataset of 27 tables which required the use of joins, case statements, and CTEs
- AppTrader Startup | Team Project Used Excel to determine the most profitable app investments

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Dick's Sporting Goods

Eastvale, CA and Mt. Juliet, TN

Administrative Assistant | May 2021 - Present

Omni-Channel Lead | August 2020 - May 2021

Footwear Lead | June 2019 - August 2020

- Collect and analyze data from sales and cashier performance weekly
- Utilize Taleo to pull applications and conduct the first interview
- Review any missed online orders and in-store pickups & make corrections to store inventory

Ross Medical Education Center

Lafayette, IN

Career Services | September 2016- September 2018

- Assisted students in gaining the tools necessary to enter the workplace
- Process student's externship paperwork
- Prepare files for audits including making necessary changes

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Nashville, TN

Data Analytics

Eastern University

St. Davids, PA

Masters of Data Science (In Progress)

Completed coursework includes: Fundamentals of Data Science and Intro to Statistical Modeling

Olivet Nazarene University

Bourbonnais, IL